Matthew Kaus

matthewkausfox@gmail.com | 505-879-6014| linkedIn/matthewpkaus | github/MatthewKaus | Portfolio

SUMMARY

Web developer with data science experience educated at the University of New Mexico. Recently earned a certificate in full-stack web development from the University of Arizona, with knowledge in JavaScript, CSS, and ReactJS. Excited to develop responsive and dynamic websites, with a clean and modern user experience.

SKILLS

Proficient in: JavaScript, Git, ReactJS, jQuery, NodeJS, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Bulma, Heroku, MySQL, MongoDB

Familiar with, and interested in learning more about: Python, C++, Angular JS, Vue.js, AWS

Tools: Git, LATEX, Slack, Zoom, GitHub

EDUCATION

Full Stack Web Development

Tuscon, AR | Aug 2021

UNIVERSITY OF ARIZONA

After studying in college, I decided to take on the challenge and attend a coding boot-camp. Subjects studied included: MERN and SERN stack.

Liberal Arts Gallup, NM | Dec, 2020

University of New Mexico

With my enrollment in a dual credit high school, I was able to attend college to pursue my liberal arts. Given the opportunity to be part of the National Security Studies Program at UNM, my introduction to computer science stimulated my interest in the field.

WORK EXPERIENCE

TRILOGY EDUCATION | FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPMENT (TA)

Remote | Apr 2021 - Present

- As a Teachers Assistant, during office hours I help students debug assignments and projects, and encourage them as they are working through a Full Stack Coding Curriculum.
- Assist students with online learning using tools including Zoom, Google Docs, Visual Studio Code, GitHub, and Git Bash.
- Assist instructor during class lecture, and guide students as they work through class coding activities.

WALMART | REMODEL (TEMPORARY)

Gallup, NM | Apr 2022 - June 2022

- Built relationships with customers to increase likelihood of repeat business.
- Self-sufficient and can work alone without being supervised.
- Appreciates problem-solving in group environments.

UNIVERSITY OF NEW MEXICO | RESEARCH

Albuquerque, NM | Feb 2020 - May 2020

- Studied and utilized statistics, LATEX, R Programming within a three month span for Data Science.
- Presented technical research during conferences.

PROJECTS

BENEFACTOR ☑

HTML5, JAVASCRIPT, CSS3, MySQL, HANDLEBARS, EXPRESSJS

Benefactor is a gift giving service, that allows users to gift to friends, family, or to make a strangers day. Allowing users to make and share lists for future giving plans.

- Created the wire frame as well as creative lead for the user interface.
- Outlined the database and requirements for the model lead.

MAKE ME! □

HTML5, JAVASCRIPT, JQUERY, CSS3, BULMA

Make Me Is a small application made to display a unique profile through a series of prompts.

- Established wire frame as well as user interface.
- Created communication channel using Discord.